# William Cruz

Psychology - Data Sciences - Foreign Language Tutor

#### about

6th Floor, Room 10 637 XiaoDong Road Tainan, YongKang District. Taiwan 0966159200

wi.cruzm@gmail.com

### languages

Fluent Spanish Fluent English Intermediate Chinese

### programming

MS Office, R, Python MATLAB and LATEX

Github:billytaipei101

## **summary**

Psychologist with experience as data manager and background in educational and psychological testing. Skilled in statistical analyses, automation procedures and scripting for cognitive and psychological assessment procedures using MATLAB and R. Strong research background with a Degree in Master of Science from National Cheng-chi University. Private language tutor including both Spanish and English.

## education

since 2018	<b>Ph.D.</b> Student in College of Social Sciences Mind Sciences at National Cheng Kung University (NCK Spatial Navigation	· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·
2012–2015	M.Sc. Experimental Psychology Majoring in Experimental Psychology and Ey	National ChengChi University, Taipei e Movement Research
2006–2011	<b>B.Sc. Psychology</b> Majoring in Psychometrics and Statistical Ana	National Colombian University, Bogota alyses
2008–2011	Course of Foreign Language - English Certificate of Approval	National Colombian University, Bogota
2015	Mandarin Proficiency Certificate Test of Certificate, Level 3 - Intermediate	Chinese as Foreign Language - TOCFL
2018	<b>English Proficiency Certificate</b> Test of <i>Total Score</i> 101/120. Reading – High (26/Speaking – Fair (23/30), Writing – Good (25/3)	/30), Listening – High (27/30),

# **experience**

since Nov 2020 Cambridge Language School, Tainan.

Teaching Intermediate Conversation.

since May 2020 AMC, Taiwan.

Online English Tutor.

English Teacher.

English Tutor.

since Sept 2018 Cambridge Language School, Tainan.

Teaching Basic Spanish - Beginner Level.

04 2016–12 2018 **ICFES, Test Design Sub directorate, Bogota.** Psychometrics and Data Manager. *Development of an Algorithm for Items' Data Management and test assembly.* 

10 2015-04 2016 American Eagle School, Taoyuan.

English Teacher.

Spanish Teacher.

Teaching Basic English - Beginner Level.

01–09 2015 Trend Micro, Research Department, Taipei.

Spanish Email Investigator,

Research Internship.

Labeling task for an Algorithm that identify SPAM.

09 2012–07 2015 Department of Psychology, National ChengChi University, Taipei. Research Assistant.

Research Assistant in the Eye Movement and Reading Laboratory.

11 2011-04 2012 Department of Psychology, National Colombian University, Bogota.

Psychometrics.

Performed several Statistical Analyses on the data from the Prisoners in Colombian Jails for Risk Profile Generation.

09 2011-05 2012 Department of Psychology, Antonio Nariño University, Bogota. Research

Assistant.

Performed Statistical Analyses on the data from Professors and Students.

03-08 2011 Department of Psychology, National Colombian University, Bogota.

Auditor

Document Validation in a National Recruitment Process.

# applications

2018 Algorithm for the Automated Assembly of National Performance Test

ICFES, Test Design Sub directorate, Bogota.

Algorithm for the Pre Assembly of Tests including Saber  $3^{\circ}$ ,  $5^{\circ}$ ,  $9^{\circ}$ ,  $11^{\circ}$ , Pro and TyT in R language.

## publications and conferences

07 2019 15<sup>th</sup> Asia Pacific Conference on Vision - APCV The Effect of Word's Visual

Complexity Distribution on Saccade Targeting in Reading Chinese Sentences. Osaka, Japan

Poster Presentation

 $5^{th}$  Asia Congress of Health Psychology The Effects of Cognitive

Behavior Therapy on Chronic Fatigye Syndrome and its Potential Moderators: A meta-analysis.

Daejeon, South Korea

Poster Presentation

05 2011	$5^{th}$ Latin American Congress of Psychology and Health - ALAPSA. Psychometric Analysis of the Eurotest: A screening test for the assessment of mild impairment. Xalapa, Mexico Oral Presentation	
2014	Reference guide for non-expert researchers in multivariate statistics Diversitas, Perspectivas en Psicología, Vol. 10, No. 10, pp. 13–27 Paper	
2014	Adaptación al contexto colombiano del test de cribado para la evaluación de la demencia (Eurotest)  Avances en Medición, Vol. 9, pp. 58–72  Paper	